Abhishek Bagchi

abhishekbagchi@icloud.com

January 10, 2018

Objective

To work with pioneering organizations and be a part of a team which contributes to the growth of the organization while simultaneously expanding my knowledge and skills.

Work Experience

2017-Present | Software Engineer

ARM Ltd

Modelling of AMBA AHB components

System level performance modelling and investigation

Performance modelling and initial investigation of NoC architectures

2015-2017 | Graduate Software Engineer

ARM Ltd

Performance modelling and initial investigation of NoC architectures Performance modelling of master ports for L3 caches using C++ $\,$

Power management investigations using Gem5

2014 | Student Trainee

Samsung R&D Institute India

Bangalore, India

2012 Intern

Cologne University Of Applied Sciences

Cologne, Germany

Education

2014-2015 | Master of Sciences In Advanced Computing - Machine Learning, Data Mining and

High Performance Computing

University of Bristol

2010-2014 Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Science and Engineering

Manipal Institute of Technology

Master's Thesis

Title | Aligning video segments for appearance based navigation

Summary

This thesis aimed to tackle the problem of appearance based navigation. The intention was to investigate the suitability/practicality of navigation relying only on visual cues, and develop a prototype for a navigation system. Prototyped using Qt and OpenCV.

Projects

• Create a tool to comprehensively capture Android memory allocations and deallocations

Samsung R&D Institute India - Bangalore

The project involved modifying Android(4.2) to allow logging memory allocations and deallocations, and creating a desktop application (using Qt and C++) that would capture those logs, and also allow the user to visualize the data.

• SkEtch3D

Cologne University Of Applied Sciences

The given task was to develop a module which would be given drawn natural sketches as input and convert them to spline curves. The project was done using Java, OpenCV and ImageJ.

• Simulate a superscalar processor

University of Bristol

Course project as a part of the course Advanced Computer Architecture at the University of Bristol. The work involved designing and implimenting a simulator for a superscalar processor. Done using Ada.

Volunteer Activities

• Mentor in the program EES Applied

Organisation: EDT (The Engineering Development Trust)

Mentor to a group of 16-18 year old students designing and prototyping projects for the blind set by the Royal National Institute of Blind People (RNIB).

Computer Skills

- **Programming Languages:** C++ (proficient), JAVA (Intermediate), Python 2.7 (Intermediate), C (Intermediate), Go (Basics), Common LISP (Basics), Ada (Basics), VHDL (Prior Experience)
- Frameworks/Platforms: GUI development using Qt framework for C++, Application and Web Development using C# on the .NET framework(prior experience)

Co-curricular Activities

Conducted a workshop on Core Java and Event-driven Programming Using Java, Application Development using Android.

Assisted in workshops on Basics of Artificial Intelligence and implementation using C, Problem Solving Using Computers, Fundamental Data Structures using C

Headed the category System Admin, which involved developing a web based(HTML, PHP) system to allow registrations and managing participant data for Revels, the official cultural fest of Manipal Institute of Technology.

Organizational/Management Activities

Board member of the students body, Institution of Engineers-Computer Science and Engineering, in capacity of Technical Head for the year 2012-13, responsible for a team of over 90 students.